[Music]
Why did the biggest fraud of 3 years come to the city of ICC Lombard?
How much progress did Bombay Burmah make on its investment in Co-First?
Why was Nifty's top loser on Monday?
Why did BKT results remain separate from Swiggy's?
Who cut Swiggy's?
Apart from the answers to all these questions, there are many other
news which will be discussed in today's episode.
Hello, welcome to Corporate Centre.
I am Sandeep Grover.
First of all, let's talk about
today's big corporate news. The
board of ICC Bank, the second largest bank in the region, on Sunday, 1828, approved
increasing its stake in ICC Lombard, the group's general insurance company.
Till March 31, 2023, ICC Bank has a
48.02 percent stake in ICC Lombard.
Now the bank's board has given the
green signal to increase its stake in ICC Lombard in several phases up to 35 percent.
ICC Bank will
buy the stake before at least September 9, 2024.
Due to this news, the share of ICC Lombard increased on
Monday.  A massive jump of up to 14% was witnessed,
which was the
biggest single-day gain since March 2020. The reason for this massive
surge is that it was renamed as ICC Bank. On
March 10, ICC Bank had
informed the exchanges that the bank had received an extension
from the RBI till September 9, 2014, to reduce its stake
below 30% in ICC Lombard.
However, contrary to that, the board has now
approved the increase. In fact,
according to the guidelines of the banking regulator RBI,
banks can hold less than 30%
or more than 50% stake in insurance companies.
Three major news items have come in two days. The first news is
that after the flights of BB11 were banned on 3 May,
other
airlines have increased their flights on its routes,
although airfares on the notes have
increased by up to five times. The second
news is that
Bombay Burmah
Trading Corporation (BB), another company of the Wadia Group, has made a
provision of Rs 1,886 crore on its investment in BB11. Let us inform you that
BBC  Jet Airways currently holds a 33
% stake in Gofers. The third news is
that the
companies that leased aircraft to Jet Airways have approached the Delhi High Court to get their aircraft released. They have
n't received any relief from the National Company No Appeals Committee (NCLT), and now these companies have
claimed that NCLT has no authority to
settle the issue of aircraft dealmakers. The
third news is
also related to the airline sector.
Regarding the revival of debt-ridden Jet Airways, NCLT has granted more time to the
Consortium of Creditors (JKC) to
pay the outstanding amount.
JKC has to
pay an outstanding amount of Rs 150 crore to the State Bank of India,
for which it has been given an extension of 97 days, or about 3 months.
Last year,
JKC, which had made a crucial offer for Jet Airways, has given the company's lenders a
performance guarantee, meaning an outstanding
balance of Rs 150 crore was pending on the loan amount by December 2022.  In 2018,
NCLT ordered the lenders to
transfer ownership rights to JKC.
According to this order, JKC was required to
pay ₹185 crore for the lenders by 15 May 2023. However, due to JKC's
missing landline, SBI acquired the lender from Inc.L.A. to secure JKC's
bank balance.
JKC
filed a petition with Inc.L.A., seeking a stay
on SBI's guarantee of ₹150 crore. However,
on 22 May, Inc.
reserved its decision, and now, on 26
May, it has issued this decision.
Fourth news: Following the strong performance of GLR in the fourth quarter results,
another good news has come for Tata Motors. The
rating agency Midas Investor
Services has
upgraded Tata Motors'
outlook from stable to positive.
According to this, Tata Motors'
credit profile is expected to continue improving for the next 12 to 18
months. Furthermore,
Mulliska also says that all three
segments, i.e., commercial, are expected to see strong growth.  Improvement in medical passenger
vehicles and
Land Rover may continue.
However, the Reserve Bank of India has maintained the company's corporate family
rating at B1 and said that
if the company continues to improve its credit profile for a
longer period, the
credit rating may improve further.
Fifth news: India's largest pharmaceutical company
Sun Pharma on Saturday, 27th, announced its intention to buy the
remaining stake of Israel's Terra Pharma.
Sun
Pharma has informed the board of Terra Pharma through
a letter regarding this proposal.
Currently, Sun Pharma holds
78% stake in Terra Pharma and has
offered to buy the remaining stake i.e. 21.52% at a price of 38%,
which
is at a premium of 31.2% over the closing price of 25th April.
Under this proposal, Terra Pharma will operate as a subsidiary of Sun Pharma
and will be listed on the New York Stock
Exchange (NYSE), where the company is listed.
Listing will also happen.
Sixth news: Balance Capital, a US-based asset management
firm, has announced a second cut
in the valuation of food delivery platform Swiggy.
According to the information given to market regulator AIX,
Swiggy's valuation has been reduced by 10.1 percent to
$6.38 billion by March 2023. This is
not the first time that Swiggy's
valuation has been reduced. Earlier,
a fund run by Baron Capital Group had reduced Swiggy's
valuation by 34 percent to $7.1 billion by December 2022.
We had informed you about this
in episode number 17 of Corporate Central.
Also, another applicant,
Invesco, had also
reduced Swiggy's valuation by 33 percent to $5.30 billion by January 2023,
which was earlier at $8.2 billion.
Seventh: When is HDFC Limited's majority stake
in education loan Credila Financial Services?
BP Equity is leading the race to buy more than 50% stake in BP Equity. BP
Equity was earlier
known as Bearing Private Equity Asia. It is
believed that the deal could be for an
amount of up to ₹12,000 crore in dollars.
Apart from BP Equity, Blackstone and CVCB were also involved in the
race to buy Cadila Financial Services.
This deal is in the final stage and the
deal will be announced in June, i.e. before the merger of HDFC Bank and HDFC Ltd.
HDFC Ltd has
100% stake in Cadila Financial Services, an education finance company,
which has to be
reduced to 10% in 2 years as per RBI conditions. So this was
today's complete update related to corporate. Now let's
talk about the market and take a look at some such stocks which saw
strong action today
and also understand the reason behind it.
First news:
After the disappointing fourth quarter results, on Monday, the city of 19 witnessed the
biggest decline in 6 months since November 21, 2022.  The
stock went up to 4:30 in the trading,
during which it reached a low of Rs 156.50 paise
and the closing was also around three
days. With this decline, the
company has gone from profit to loss.
During the quarter, the company has
registered a loss of around Rs 28 crore as against a profit of Rs 1144.8 crore. This is
because the company has registered a biggest loss of Rs 200235 crore
during the quarter.
Actually, the company has made a provision of Rs 12160 crore for the dispute related to service and GST on royalty payment as well as
bus payment.
This matter is related
to royalty payment between April 1, 2016 and March 31, 2023.
However, the company will continue the legal battle on the matter.
In the fourth quarter, the company
's income decreased by 5.9 percent from Rs 38583 crore to
around Rs 36293 crore. Operating
profit for the fourth quarter
declined by 19.9 percent from Rs 200411 crore
to Rs 16340 crore and operating margins have also
fallen.  It has come down to 45%
which was at 52.9% in the third quarter.
Apart from this, there is also news that the
company has announced to start gas production from the basin from June 15. The
company has also invited bids for this and has
demanded the price of 12 per unit. In the
second news, after the fourth quarter results, there was a
decline of up to 10% in the share of City Union Bank.
Despite this, the results of only one bank were
good and the closing was also
seen with a decline of 10%,
during which the share closed at Rs 125.30 paise,
that is, the net profit increased by
two points from Rs 500.7 crore to Rs
514.2 crore, but the profit
increased by only 4.3% from Rs 2009 crore to Rs 218 crore
because there has been a decrease of 7% in provisioning.
Here, the
gross NPA of your bank
remained at 4.2 crore, whereas the net HPA is 2.67 crore.  The interest
rate remained at 2.36 percent. The
results were lower than market estimates, due to which a
decline was seen in the city. The second
disappointment was on the MAQ (Net Interest
Margin) front. NIMS
fell from 3.88 percent to 3.65 percent. The
third reason is that according to the broker, the results
are weak and the future is also challenging.
ICC Securities has downgraded the bank's rating
from 'Ad' to 'Hold' and has given a target of 140.
Similarly, Nirmal Bang has also
downgraded the rating, has removed the rating and accumulated it
and has set the target at 151.
Also, Lara Capital has kept the cumulative rating on hold
and has set the target for the bank at 145.
In the third news, on Monday 29, the stock made a move of more than 11 percent.
During the day, the stock
locked an intraday high of ₹40 and closed with a weakness of around 10 percent. The
reason is the extremely disappointing results of the fourth quarter.
In fact, the fourth quarter of the year was held in the fourth quarter.
In the last 10 years, there has been an increase in losses due to competition. In the fourth quarter, the company has incurred a
loss of Rs 441.5 crore. If we
look at the same period last year, the company's loss was Rs
141.3 crore. However, during this period, the
company's income has increased by 47.6 percent from Rs 1283.6 crore to
around Rs 1895 crore. The
biggest problem for the company is its performance on the operating front. The
operating profit of the company has come down
from Rs 534 crore to Rs 20059 crore and a
huge decline has also been recorded in the margin.
In the fourth quarter, the operating margin has remained
around 41.6%. Fourth news: Before the results,
in the last two months, the share of BKD i.e.
Balkrishna Industries has increased by about 26%
because the results are expected to be good,
as has been seen in other companies of the sector. However,
unlike other companies of the sector, there has been a decline on all fronts,
due to which the share
saw a decline of up to 9% on Monday
and the closing was also around 7:30 percent.
Talking about the fourth quarter, the company's revenue
declined by 2.4% from Rs 2003.74 crore to Rs 18 crore from Rs 2003.
Operating profit declined by 6% from Rs 500 crore to Rs
471 crore. Operating
margins fell by 21% to 20.3%
and profits declined by 32% from around Rs 3400 crore
to Rs 256 crore, whereas
other companies in the sector have
seen at least 100% or double increase in profits. The
management's country is also weakening.
According to the management, channel
inventory problems are continuing due to which
sales have declined. The
management has expressed the possibility of channel inventory problems getting
resolved by June-July, but the market is
assuming that the
results of the first quarter of FY 2024 may also face pressure.
Problems in Europe are expected to get
resolved by the latter half of FY 2024, i.e. the second quarter.
This is quite clear.  Because
about 50% of the company's revenue comes from abroad, the
European market is
very important for the company.
With this, Corporate Central has only this much
time to leave you today, but before we leave, let me
tell you
which events and
triggers can have a special impact on Tuesday's market.
First, on the 29th,
IRCTC released a major result
after the market was closed, so its
impact will be seen in Tuesday's market.
And the UK market
is closed on Monday, so especially
from the Indian market's perspective, there will
not be any major impact on the Asian market.
As far as the 30th is concerned, the results of
two big companies in Nifty,
Apollo Hospitals and Adani Ports, will be
released. Talking about the futures market,
Toilet Farm is a big company
whose results will be released. Along with this result,
fund raising will also be considered in the board meeting.
Along with this result, the results of Barmal Lori are
also to be released.
Along with the outcome of the vote meeting, the board can decide on either buy-bye or bonus
shares.
Furthermore, as far as the 30th is concerned, the
dividend announced by ITC Vidhansabha has an
ex-date, meaning the
dividend adjustment can be
seen in the shares of both ITC and Vedanta. Regarding
global traders, there are
some data that are going to be released. Among them, there will be the
March
House Price Index data. The
market will be closely monitoring this.
Consumer confidence data for the month of March will
also be released. Along with this,
European consumer
confidence data for the month of March will also be released. These are some
special global data that will be
particularly monitored by the global market.
With this, it's time to wrap up the corporate world. I
hope you
enjoyed today's episode and it gave you a
complete picture of the corporate world as well as the action-packed shares. So, we'll
meet you again on Tuesday, the 30th, at the same time with new updates on the market.  Till then keep
watching Money Nahi for the latest news and some action-packed stocks.
[Music]